# MEGAN AMARAL

**ANALYTICS ENGINEER** 

(831) 345-7140

MEGAN.AMARAL@GMAIL.COM

LINKEDIN.COM/IN/MEGAN-AMARAL

NASHVILLE, TN | REMOTE

# **PROFILE**

Data lover with high-growth startup experience, and a passion for using data to inform business decisions. A quick learner who has a high standard for delivering quality and value. Driven by curiosity and excited by supporting business expansion.

# **EDUCATION**

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL DATA ANALYTICS BOOTCAMP JAN-JUNE 2021

SAN JOSE STATE UNIVERSITY
MASTER OF LIBRARY AND
INFORMATION SCIENCE

UNIVERSITY OF PUGET SOUND
BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, BIOLOGY

# AWARDS

EVENTBRITE MAKE-IT-HAPPEN-SPIRIT AWARD NOMINEE | AUG 2019

## SKILLS & TOOLS

- Python: Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib
- SQL: Postgres, MySQL
- Git/Github
- Jupyter
- Microsoft Excel: Pivot Tables, VLookups, Visualizations
- PowerBI
- Agile Methodologies
- JIRA & Confluence
- Requirements Reviews
- Product Development
- Test Planning & Execution

### **EXPERIENCE**

# NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL | JAN 2021 - PRESENT DATA ANALYTICS APPRENTICE

• Use authentic data from local organizations to produce projectbased reports and recommendations. Communicate findings through presentations and dashboard visualizations.

#### **EVENTBRITE | JUN 2011 - PRESENT**

Global platform for event creators to manage event registration, attendee payments, and check-in. Web and app-based marketplace for event-goers to find their next live experience.

#### **ANALYTICS ENGINEER II**

• Support business stakeholders by developing and maintaining data marts, leveraging ETL processes and SQL to produce domain-specific data, ready for internal analysis.

#### SENIOR QUALITY ASSURANCE ENGINEER, MONEY SYSTEMS

FEB 2020 - MAR 2021

- Team leader of functional quality assurance for the accuracy of 27million financial transactions per quarter in 180 countries, via partnered and facilitated payment gateways.
- Developed a bug prioritization scale based on impact to data quality, as a process-oriented effort to improve to financial records.

#### SENIOR QUALITY ASSURANCE ENGINEER, PLATFORM

JUL 2018 - JAN 2020

- Analyzed root causes of bug reports for teams in the Platform business unit to surface process improvement opportunities for higher quality output.
- Formalized company-wide feature ownership by mapping features and microservices to development teams for longterm maintenance and stewardship.

# QUALITY ASSURANCE ENGINEER I & II, PAYMENTS & PRICING JUN 2014 - JUN 2018

- Designed functional test strategies for pricing and fee models.
   Developed a strategy using variables to help test plans scale with growing international customer base and local regulations.
- Tested payment gateway integrations in existing and new markets while expanding payment method options for buyers.

#### **TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER**

JUN 2012 - MAY 2014

- Managed the triage process for customer reported issues, using judgement, business acumen, and contact volumes to help Development teams prioritize fixes.
- Provided documentation and trainings to support the growing team.

#### **CUSTOMER SUPPORT REPRESENTATIVE & ASSOCIATE**

JUN 2011 - MAY 2014

- Assisted the Development and QA teams with the isolation and prioritization of bugs for customer-facing issues, while providing a customer's perspective and estimated impacts to the brand.
- Designed and led trainings for Client Services on-boarding and provided continuing mentorship to team members.